우리 귀여운 조카...
Who the winny-binny boy?
You the winny-winny-binny-binny boy!
깨물어 주고 싶은 아가!
울지 마
울지 말렴
Don't cry.
왜 계속 울지?
Why is he still crying?
Let me hold him for a sec.
내가 안을게
이리 와
Here we go.
봤지?
There we are.
Maybe it's me.
내가 싫은가?
Don't be silly. Ben loves you.
He's just being Mr. Cranky Pants.
아니, 벤은 널 좋아해
괜히 변덕부리는 거야
그런 여자랑 사귄 적 있어
You know, I once dated
a Miss Cranky Pants.
Lovely girl. IKind of moody.
예쁜데 변덕이 죽 끓더라
There we go, all better.
됐어, 이제 괜찮아
There's my little boy.
우리 아기...
Can I see something?
이거 볼래?
자동이네!
Cool!
He hates me.
My nephew hates me!
날 싫어하잖아!
조카가 날 싫어한다고!
Come on, don't do this.
그런 소리 마
내 자식도 날 싫어하면
그 땐 어쩌지?
What if my own baby hates me?
What do I do then?
모니카, 왜 이러셔
Monica, stop! This is nuts.
Do you know how long it'll be
before you have to deal with this?
그런 일 언제 겪을지도
아직 모르잖아
You don't even have a boyfriend yet.
여태 남자친구도 없으면서
Joey, she does not look fat.
얘 임신한 것 같진 않지?
The One With the Baby on the Bus
Here you go.
- 여기
- 모니카, 잘 봐
Goo, goo, goo!
정말 웃긴다!
공 잠깐 줘 볼래?
That is so funny!
Let me see that a sec.
You okay?
- 로스, 괜찮아?
- 몰라
I don't know.
What's in this pie?
이 파이 뭐로 만들었어?
버터, 계란, 밀가루
라임, 키위...
I don't know. Butter and eggs
and flour and lime and kiwi
키위를 넣었다고?
Kiwi? Kiwi?!
라임 파이라고 했잖아
You said it was a key lime pie.
키위 라임 파이라고 했지
특별히 만들었어
No, I didn't. I said kiwi lime.
That's what makes it so special.
That's what's gonna kill me.
특별히 날 죽이려고?
I'm allergic to kiwi.
난 키위 알레르기야
아니잖아
바닷가재, 땅콩은 몰라도...
No, you're not. You're allergic
to lobster and peanuts and
- 이걸 어째!
- 점점 더 심해져
Oh, my God!
It's definitely getting worse.
Is your tongue swelling up?
혀가 부어 올라?
내 입이 점점 작아져!
Either that or my mouth
is getting smaller!
옷 입어
당장 병원에 가자!
Get your coat.
We're going to the hospital.
-Will he be okay?
-He's gotta get a shot.
- 괜찮아질까?
- 그럼, 주사만 맞으면 돼
You know, actually,
it's getting better. It is.
이제 괜찮아진 것 같아
병원에 안 가도 되겠어
Let's not go.
Anyone up for Scrabble?
낱말 잇기 놀이 할까?
Jacket, now!
재킷 입어!
벤은? 아기를 데리고
병원에 갈 순 없잖아
What about Ben? We can't
bring a baby to the hospital.
We'll watch him.
우리가 볼게
I don't think so.
절대 안 돼!
난 누나만 일곱이야
애는 지겹게 봤다고
I have seven Catholic sisters.
I've taken care of hundreds of kids.
Come on, we want to do it.
Don't we?
우리가 봐 줄게, 그렇지?
농구 할 생각이었는데
공도 날아가고 없잖아
I was gonna play basketball...
... but I guess that's out the window.
애 데리고 밖에 나갈 땐
꼭 모자를 씌워
If you take him out for a walk,
remember to bring his hat.
There's milk in the refrigerator
and diapers in the bag.
우유는 냉장고에 있고
기저귀는 가방에 있어
모자, 우유, 그리고...
알았어!
Hat, milk....
Got it!
걱정하지 마!
Consider it done!
You understood?
무슨 말인지 알아들었어?
응, 우리 삼촌도
혀가 엄청 컸거든
My uncle Sal has a really big tongue.
Is he the one
with the beautiful wife?
아내가 예쁘다는 분?
레이첼, 내가 오후에 부를
노래 들어 볼래?
You want to hear the song
I'm singing this afternoon?
아침에 샤워하다 만들었어
I wrote it this morning in the shower.
좋아
난 샤워를 하면서
작곡을 한다네
I'm in the shower
And I'm writing a song
Stop me if you've heard it
들었으면 날 말려 줘요
촉촉한 피부, 젖은 머리
My skin is soapy and my hair is wet
'겟너'를 거꾸로 쓰면
'너겟'이라네
And Tegrin spelled backward is nirget
레이첼, 나 잠깐 볼까?
Rachel, sweetheart,
could I see you for a minute?
무슨 일이죠?
What's up?
일요일 오후에 노래할
진짜 가수를 고용했어
FYK:
I've decided to pay a professional
musician to play here on Sundays.
스테파니 머시기인데
실력이 좋다더군
Her name is Stephanie something.
She's supposed to be very good.
피비는 어쩌고요?
But what about Phoebe?
레이첼, 친구실력이 단지
형편없어서 그런게 아냐
It's not that your friend is bad.
아주 형편없어!
It's that she's so bad...
피비 때문에 손가락을 눈에 넣어
뇌까지 휘저어 놓고 싶다고!
...she makes me want to put my finger
through my eye into my brain...
...and swirl it around.
피비의 팬이 아니시군요
Okay, so you're not a fan.
그래도 이건 너무해요
But, I mean, come on.
You cannot do this to her.
아뇨, 아뇨!
나보고 말하라고요?
I have to do this to her?
비누거품, 린스를 반복
Lather, rinse, repeat
And lather, rinse, repeat
비누거품, 린스를 반복
지겨울 때까지!
As needed
영 손이 허전한데 말야
아기 침대는 안 챙겼어?
We didn't bring enough stuff.
Did you forget to pack
the baby's anvil?
내가 괜히 이러겠어?
I'm telling you, it'll be worth it.
여자들은 아기를 좋아하고
It's a known fact
that women love babies.
Women love guys who love babies.
It's the sensitive thing.
또 아기 좋아하는 남자라면
사족을 못 쓴다고
저쪽으로 조준해
한 명쯤은 사살되겠지
Aim him at that pack of babes.
Maybe one of them will break away.
Wait, forget them.
We got one. Hard left.
아냐, 좌측에 목표물 출현!
아기 이리 줘
-Give me the baby.
-No, I got him.
- 내가 안고 있을게
- 나 심각해!
Come on, seriously.
심각하게 애를 원한다고?
Oh, seriously, you want him?
- 안녕!
- 안녕하세요?
이 귀염둥이는 누구죠?
Who is this little cutie-pie?
말하기 쑥스럽지만...
Well, don't think me immodest, but...
접니다
... me.
Want to smell him?
냄새 맡아 볼래요?
I assume we're talking about the baby?
물론 아기 말이겠죠?
네, 냄새가 아주 좋아요
머리 한번 맡아 봐요
He's got that great baby smell.
Get a whiff of his head.
냄새만 맡아도 배가 불러와요
My uterus just skipped a beat.
내 말 맞지?
What'd I tell you?
아기를 보다니
자상하시기도 하셔라
It's great you're doing this.
우린 멋진 놈들이죠
Well, we are great guys.
게이인 내 남동생도
아기를 입양한다던데
My brother and his boyfriend
have been trying to adopt.
What agency did you two go through?
어느 기관을 통하셨죠?
여긴 내 공연장이야
But this is my gig.
This is where I play.
My name is written out there in chalk.
밖에 분필로 내 이름도
쓰여 있다고
분필을 어떻게 지우려고?
You know, you can't just erase chalk.
정말 미안해
Honey, I'm sorry.
그 여자에게 돈도 준다고?
And he's going to
be paying this woman?
Why doesn't he just give her
a throne and a crown?
아예 왕관에다가
황금공이 달린
지팡이까지 주지 그러니
And, like, a gold stick
with a ball on top?
'테리, 그 나쁜 인간! '
다들 이렇게 말하거든
Terry is a jerk! That's why
we always say, "Terry's a jerk!"
That's where that came from.
그 사람의 생각이라고
너도 노력한 거 알아
You probably did everything you could.
잠깐 기다려
내가 다시 말해 볼게
You know what? Let me just
see what else I could do.
스테파니 머시기 다음에
연주하게 하면요?
Just let her go on after
Stephanie whatever her name is.
돈주는 것도 아닌데
손해볼 것 없잖아요
You won't be here.
You don't pay her.
- 글쎄...
- 카푸치노 기계 청소할게요!
I don't know.
I'll clean the cappuccino machine!
평소엔 안 했단 말야?
You don't clean
the cappuccino machine?
물론 청소했죠
Of course I clean it.
I mean, I will clean it.
아주 깨끗하게 한다는
소리예요
I mean, I will clean it.
알았어, 알았다고!
All right, fine, fine, fine!
-Done.
-Really?
- 해결됐어
- 정말?
그럼, 내가 누군데!
Who's working for you, babe?
Oh, my God! This is so exciting!
How much am I gonna get?
너무 잘됐다!
공연료는 얼마 준대?
뭐?
What?
연주자에게 돈을 준다면서
He's paying the people
who were playing.
그게 아냐
I meant, he's paying that other woman
because she's a professional.
그녀는 직업 가수라서
돈을 주는 거야
I'm not gonna be the only one
who's not getting paid.
나만 안 받을 순 없잖아?
- 피비...
- 미안하지만 싫어!
I'm sorry, no!
난 대타로 나서는
그런 2류가 아니라고!
No, I'm not some sloppy second,
you know, charity band.
돈내고 내 노래 듣겠다는
사람이 지천에 깔려 있어
There are thousands of places
in this city...
...where people would pay
to hear me play.
난 날 위해 노래해요
동정심은 필요 없어
When I play, I play for me
I don't need your charity
Thank you!
고맙습니다
주사는 맞기 싫어
I'm not getting a shot.
Maybe they can take the needle...
물총처럼 내 입에다
쏴 주면 되잖아
...and squirt it into my mouth.
Like a squirt gun.
안녕하세요
칼린 박사입니다
Hello there. I'm Dr. Carlin.
알레르기가 문제라고요?
I see someone's having
a little allergic reaction.
잠깐 얘기 좀 할까요?
Doctor, can I see you
for just a moment?
오빠는 주사바늘이라면
경기를 일으켜요
My brother has
a slight phobia about needles.
물총에 대해 말해드려!
Did you tell him
about my squirt gun idea?
경구 약으로 치료할
방법은 없을까요?
My brother, the Ph.D.,
would like to know...
...if there's any way
to treat this orally?
아뇨, 현 상태에선
주사를 맞아야만 해요
Under these circumstances, it has to be
an injection, and it has to be now.
그것도 당장!
뭐래?
So?
얼른 앉아, 의사 선생님이
주사를 맞아야 한대
Go and have a seat. The doctor
says it's got to be a needle.
You're just going to have to be brave.
Can you do that for me?
그러니 눈 딱 감고 참아
날 위해 해줄 수 있지?
- 알았어
- 어쩜, 착하기도 해라!
Oh, boy! You are doing so good.
- 손 잡아 줄까?
- 응!
You want to squeeze my hand?
Ross, don't squeeze it so hard.
너무 세게 쥐진 말아
Honey, really.
Don't squeeze it so hard!
못 들었어?
세게 쥐지 말라니까!
나 죽어!
Let go of my hand!
기발한 생각이었어
Good plan. Next time
we want to pick up women...
다음부턴 공원에 가서
키스를 하자고
...we should go to
the park and make out.
Taxi! Taxi!
택시!
야, 저 여자 좀 봐
Look at that talent.
한번 불러 봤어요
엄청 빨리 오네요
Just practicing. You're good.
Carry on.
잠깐만요!
Wait, wait, wait!
Hey, you. He's just adorable.
안녕, 아가야?
아기가 너무 귀여워요
그래도 얘는 자기가
섹시하지 않다고 불만이죠
Can you tell him that?
Because he thinks he looks too pink.
- 데이트 나온 거예요?
- 아니에요!
-What are you guys out doing today?
-We're not out.
우린 친구의 아들을 돌봐 주는
신체 건강한 두 남자친구죠
We're two heterosexual guys
hanging with the son...
...of our other heterosexual friend,
doing the usual straight-guy stuff.
- 끝났어?
- 응
You done?
여기서 내려야 돼
There's our stop.
정말로요?
우리도 여기서 내리는데
Get out of here!
This is our stop.
이 근처에 사세요?
You guys live around here too?
그럼요, 저기 인도 옆
건물에 살아요
We live in the building
by the sidewalk.
혹시 아세요?
You know it?
이웃끼리 만났는데
술이나 한잔할까요?
Since we're neighbors, what do you say
we get together for a drink?
So you want to go to Markel's?
그럼 '마켈'로 갈까요?
좋죠, 우리 단골집인데
Sure, they love us over there.
아기는 어디 있어요?
Where's your baby?
벤! 벤!
Ben! Ben!
잘한다, 더 크게 불러
애가 듣고 벨 누르게!
That's good. Maybe he'll
hear you and pull the cord!
버스 세워요!
아기가 탔단 말이에요!
Stop the bus!
정말 안 부러졌어요?
너무 아프거든요
Are you sure he didn't break it?
It hurts.
가벼운 타박상입니다
No, it's just a good bone bruise.
이건 반지 때문에 생긴
구멍이구요
And right here is
the puncture wound from your ring.
- 정말 미안해
- 괜찮아
-I'm really sorry.
-It's okay.
미안...
발음이 정확히 돼요!
Sorry.
Sorry! I got my S's back!
그건 나중에 좋아하고
Which we can celebrate later.
좋아하고, 좋아...
Celebrate. Celebrate....
그는 몸을 맘대로
휠 수가 있었네
He was a double, double
Double-jointed boy
안녕하세요?
그 유명한 직업 가수?
So are you the
professional guitar player?
Yeah, I'm Stephanie.
네, 스테파니예요
그렇군요
Right. My name was on there,
but now it just says carrot cake.
내 이름이 적혀 있었는데
'당근 케이크'로 바뀌었죠
코드는 몇 개나 알아요?
So how many chords do you know?
전부 알죠
-All of them.
-So you know D?
그럼 'D'도 알아요?
네
그럼 'A 마이너'는?
Do you know A-minor?
네
D에서 A 마이너로
옮겨갈 줄도 알아요?
Do you know how to go
from D to A-minor?
그럼요
그렇군요
기타에 가죽 끈 달렸어요?
So does your guitar have a strap?
- 아뇨
- 난 있어요
Mine does.
코드를 꿰는 잘난 스테파니
Stephanie knows all the chords
Come on! Pick up, pick up!
받아! 받아!
여보세요?
대중교통 담당 부서죠?
안녕하세요
Transit Authority?
조사를 하는 중인데요
I'm doing research for a book.
누가 버스에 아기를 두고
내리면 어떻게 해야 하죠?
I was wondering what somebody might do
if they left a baby on a city bus.
멍청한 인간인 건 알아요
Yes, I realize that would be
a stupid character.
이렇게 하죠
Here's the deal:
We lost a car seat on a bus.
버스에 아기 카시트를
두고 내렸어요
It's white plastic and
it fits onto a stroller.
유모차에 매달 수 있는
흰색 플라스틱이에요
안에 아기가 들었고요
And there was a baby in it.
너 다시 바꾸래
He wants to talk to you.
앞으로 이 곳에서
공연하게 될...
Everybody, let's give a warm
Central Perk welcome to
테리, 이 나쁜 놈
날 잘랐어
Terry's a jerk
And he won't let me work
난 여기가 싫어
And I hate Central Perk
스테파니 쉬퍼입니다!
To Stephanie Schiffer!
제 첫사랑을 위해서 쓴
곡으로 시작하죠
I'd like to start with a song I wrote
for the first man I ever loved.
Zachary
쟈크리...
차라리 날 뜯어먹어!
Are all invited to bite me
뉴욕 보건국
버스에 아기를 두고
내렸는데 여기 있다죠?
We're the guys that called
about the baby! Is he here?!
여기 있어요
He's here.
누가 아기의 아빠시죠?
I assume one of you is the father.
- 바로 저예요
- 접니다
-That's me.
-I'm him.
실은 저희 둘 다 아빠죠
Actually, we're both the father.
- 안녕, 벤!
- 잘 있었어?
Oh, Ben! Hey, buddy.
누가 벤인지는 알겠지?
Please tell me you know
which one is our baby.
저 애는 오리 그림이고
이 애는 광대 그림이야
That one has ducks on his T-shirt
and this one has clowns.
벤은 오리 그림을
입고 있었어
And Ben was definitely wearing ducks.
아님 광대!
Or clowns.
봐, 저 애가 벤이야!
입 주위에 점이 있잖아
That one's Ben! Remember he had
that cute little mole by his mouth!
- 확실해?
- 그럼!
벤, 우리 누군지 알겠어?
Hey, Ben! Remember us?
점이 떨어졌잖아
Okay, the mole came off.
어쩌면 좋지?
What are we gonna do?
동전 던져서 결정하자
We'll flip for it.
Ducks or clowns.
- 아기를 두고 동전을 던져?
- 더 좋은 생각 있어?
-Flip for the baby?
-You got a better idea?
좋아, 하늘의 뜻에
맡기자고
All right, call it in the air.
앞면!
Heads.
앞면이 나왔어
Heads, it is.
앞면이 어떤 애인지
정해야지!
We have to assign heads to something!
참!
Right!
좋아, 이렇게 하자
앞면을 오리로 하자
오리는 머리가 있잖아
Ducks is heads
because ducks have heads.
그럼 머리가 없는
광대도 있냐?
What kind of scary-ass clowns
came to your birthday?
날 아침의 천사라
불러 주세요
Just call me angel
Of the morning, angel
Just touch my cheek
Before you leave me, baby
떠나기 전에
내 볼을 보듬어 줘요
날 아침의 천사라
불러 주세요
Just call me angel
Of the morning, angel
그리곤 천천히 돌아서요
Then slowly turn away
그댈 붙잡지는 않겠어요
I won't beg you to stay
With me
- 안녕?
- 안녕
이거
Here. I thought you might be cold.
- 추울 것 같아서
- 고마워
Thank you.
꽤 많이 벌었네?
Look at you!
You did pretty well.
8달러 27센트
$8. 27.
처음 2달러는
내가 넣었지만
But not really, because
I put in the first two.
Just to get the ball rolling
and to make myself feel better.
텅텅 비어 있으면 기분이
괜히 그럴 것 같아서
- 좀 나아졌어?
- 아니!
Do you?
난 돈 받고 노래하긴
그른 것 같아
You know, this whole playing
for money thing is so not good for me.
자, 자, 자살이란 노래를
불렀을 때는...
I don't know, when l
sang "Su-su-suicide"...
1달러 75센트 벌었어
... I got, like, $ 1. 75.
'냄새나는 고양이'는...
But then "Smelly Cat"?
25센트하고 콘돔을 벌었지
I got 25 cents and a condom.
So, you know, now I just feel
really bad for "Smelly Cat."
냄새나는 고양이들은
정말 불쌍해
사람들이 그걸 이해할까?
Honey, I don't think
everybody gets "Smelly Cat."
자기들 애완동물이
전부 건강하다면 말야
I mean, if all you've ever actually
had are healthy pets, then whoosh!
문제는 그게 아냐
But it's not even that, you know?
처음엔 재미 삼아 했는데
돈 때문에 하려니 흥이 안 나
I used to do my songs
because it made me happy.
Now it's just all
about the money, you know?
카페 손님들이
널 보고 싶어했어
Well, people missed you in there.
사실, '냄새나는 고양이'
신청도 있었고
In fact, there was actually
a request for "Smelly Cat."
정말?
누가 신청했는데?
Really? From who?
내가
Well, me.
돈은 못 벌지 몰라도
난 그 노래를 좋아해
And I know it's not your big
money song, but it's my favorite.
안녕하세요, 제가 혹시
콘돔을 거기 넣었던가요?
Did I accidentally drop
a condom in your case?
갑자기 필요해서요
It's kind of an emergency.
- 여기요
- 고마워요
-Here you go.
-Thanks a lot.
크리스틴, 찾았어!
Hey, Christine! I got it!
병원에 함께 가 줘서
고마웠어
I want to thank you
for being there for me.
- 손 다치게 해서 미안하고
- 괜찮아
And I'm sorry
I almost broke your hand.
That's okay.
I'm sorry I poisoned you.
죽일 뻔해서 미안해
내가 네 손에 연필을
꽂았던 것 기억나?
Remember the time I jammed
that pencil into your hand?
기억하냐고?
Remember it? What do
you think this is, a freckle?
그럼 이게 주근깨겠어?
내가 호박으로
오빠 얼굴을 후려친 건?
What about the time I hit you
in the face with Sylvian's pumpkin?
내가 네 자전거에다
빗자루 끼워서 넘어진 건?
Remember when I stuck
that broom in your spokes...
...and you hit your head on the curb?
기억 안 나
말로만 들었지
But I remember
people telling me about it.
벤에게 여동생이
있으면 좋겠어
I hope Ben has a little sister.
오빠를 두들겨 패고
And I hope she can kick his ass.
반창고 가져올게
I'm gonna get a new Band-Aid.
내가 네 말리부 인형의
다리를 잘라버린 건?
How about the time I cut
the legs off your Malibu Ken?
오빠 짓이었어?
That was you?
다리가 썩어들어가서
어쩔 수가 없었어
They were infected.
He wouldn't have made it.
내 조카가 돌아왔네
My little nephew.
Come here, little one!
이리 오렴, 아가야!
There's my little baby, Ben!
우리 아가!
이제 안 울잖아
Hey, he's not crying!
이제 안 운대!
신난다!
파이가 아직 남았네
There's still pie!
아빠 여기 있잖아
I'm here. I'm here.
우리 아들 잘 놀았어?
How's my little boy?
기저귀 갈아 달라고?
알았어
You want Daddy to change
your diaper? I know, I know.
조이, 챈들러 삼촌하고
재미있게 놀았어?
Did you have fun with Uncle Joey
and Uncle Chandler today?
그럼, 버스도 탔는데
He rode the bus today.
붕붕 버스를 타고...
Big boy riding the bus
물어 볼 게 있어
Hey, I have a question.
왜 엉덩이에
'분실물'이라고 적혀 있지?
How come it says,
"Property of Human Services"?
너도 들으면
배꼽 잡을 거야!
You are gonna love this.
- 벤 좀 안고 있어
- 알았어
Can you hold Ben for a sec?
이리 와
Come here. Come here.
나 키위 들었어!
도망쳐, 조이!
Stay back! I've got kiwi!
Run, Joey, run!
냄새나는 고양이
Smelly cat, smelly cat
왜 냄새나는 너에게
먹이를 줄까?
What are they feeding you?
아뇨, 또 틀렸어요
'냄새나는'을 강조해야죠
No, no. I'm sorry, it's:
Smelly cat, smelly cat
냄새나는 고양이
좋아요
훨씬 좋아졌어요
Better!
Much better. Good.
Don't feel bad,
because it's a hard song.
좀 어려운 노래니까
낙심 말아요
- 다시 할래요?
- 도입부부터
-You want to try it again?
-From the top?
도입부는 없어요
그게 이 노래의 특징이죠
There is no "top," all right?
That's the beauty of "Smelly Cat."
날 따라해요
Why don't you just follow me.
냄새나는 고양이
Smelly cat, smelly cat
왜 냄새나는 너에게
먹이를 줄까?
What are they feeding you?
냄새나는 고양이
그건 네 잘못이 아냐
Smelly cat, smelly cat
It's not your fault
너무 올리면 안 돼요
That's too much. Sorry.